🗷 arjo@[university].edu | 🌴 alrojo.github.io | 🖸 alrojo | 🛅 alexrosejo | 💆 @alexrosejo

Interest_

I'm interested in, and excited about, solving high impact problems with machine learning and computer science. In my work and research I have applied, and also contributed to, popular python frameworks for machine learning such as SciKit Learn, TensorFlow, Pytorch, OpenNMT, and Theano. These efforts have lead to publications, and business products for companies, in the fields of natural language processing (Q&A, Sentiment classification, Summarization, Machine Translation), Bioinformatics (Pretrained embeddings), and health technology (Wearables, CGM, Diabetes monitoring and classification). Recently, through my current role as a Ph.D. student in the Snyder lab at Stanford, I've expanded to extracting and analyzing data from wearable biomedical devices and fitness trackers. Beyond my individual contributions I enjoy building community around machine learning and I've supervised around 80 student projects leading to multiple papers.

Education

Stanford University Stanford, California, USA

PH.D. COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sep 2020 - now

Kongens Lyngby, Denmark

- · Advised by Professor Michael P. Snyder
- · 2020 Fulbright Scholar

Technical University of Denmark

M.Sc. Mathematical Modeling and Computation, GPA: 11.44/12.00

- Sep 2014 Dec 2016 • Nanyang Technological University, Singapore — Semester Abroad Fall 2015
- Honors program, Supervised by Professor Ole Winther

Copenhagen Business School

B.Sc. Business Administration and Information Systems, GPA: 10.70/12.00

• Lincoln University, Canterbury, New Zealand — Semester Abroad Fall 2013

Frederiksberg, Denmark

Kongens Lyngby, Denmark

Jan 2017 - Jan 2018

Sep 2011 - Jun 2014

Experience _____

Ocean.io Copenhagen, Denmark

HEAD OF DATA SCIENCE RESEARCH Feb 2020 - est. Sep 2020

Developed a machine translation algorithm.

Technical University of Denmark

DEEP LEARNING RESEARCH, INTERN

RESEARCH PROJECT MANAGER Jan 2019 - Jan 2020

Supervised and conducted research with +30 students on machine learning methodology and applying deep learning to proteomics.

Salesforce Palo Alto, California, USA

Research on deep learning for natural language processing, supervised by Richard Socher, PhD.

Teaching

Stanford University Co-Supervisor

RESEARCH COURSE SUPERVISION

Supervised 4 High School interns, 1 Undergraduate intern

Technical University of Denmark DEEP LEARNING, INTRO REINFORCEMENT LEARNING, DEEP REINFORCEMENT LEARNING

Head TA, course responsible

Significant course material contributions (Deep Learning). Course responsible (Reinforcement Learning).

2016-2019

Co-Supervisor

Supervised 13 M.Sc. Thesis' and 11 research course projects

MASTER THESIS AND RESEARCH COURSE SUPERVISION 2019-2021

Community _____

MeetUp

LEAD ORGANIZER

Nov. 2018 - Dec. 2019

Inspired by Stanford's public poster exam in CS224N in 2017 I convinced Professor Ole Winther to do the same for our 02456 Deep Learning course. With student posters, company sponsored first prize, drinks, and pizza. Given the positive feedback, I was hired by the university, started a research lab for students, and kept hosting events to celebrate the students projects. This was a lot of fun and resulted in seven events, +1.5k participants, and multiple company sponsorships. (Event page: meetup.com/Deep-Learning-DTU/).

Community research Online

LEAD ORGANIZER Jan. 2020 - now

I help independent researchers who wants to pursue graduate studies and provide free supervision and problem statements to help them publish papers and get recognized. This brings me much joy, and five of my previous students are now pursuing PhDs.

Open Source

GOOGLE TENSORFLOW

contrib.seq2seq: #4761, #4686, #4382

TensorFlow tutorial (2k stars): github.com/alrojo/tensorflow-tutorial

Academic Reviews _____

2022	NeurIPS , Neural Information Processing Systems	Reviewer
2020-23	ICLR, International Conference on Learning Representations	Reviewer
2021-22	Bioinformatics,	Reviewer
2020	ACL , Association for Computational Linguistics	Reviewer
2020-21	AAAI , Association for the advancement of artificial intelligence	Reviewer
2018-20	CONLL , Computational Natural Language Learning	Reviewer

Publications _____

2022	Nucleic Acids Research, DeepLoc 2.0: multi-label subcellular localization prediction using protein language models. V. Thumuluri, J. Armenteros, <u>A. Johansen</u> , H. Nielsen, O. Winther Nature Biotechnology, SignalP 6.0 achieves signal peptide prediction across all types using protein language	Journal
2022	models. F. Teufel, J. Armenteros, <u>A. Johansen</u> , M. Gíslason, S. Pihl, K. Tsirigos, O. Winther, S. Brunak, G. Heijne, H. Nielsen	Journal
2021	Bioinformatics , <i>NetSolP: predicting protein solubility in E. coli using language models.</i> V. Thumuluri, H. Martiny, J. Armenteros, J. Salomon, H. Nielsen, <u>A. Johansen</u>	Journal
2021	Computational Biology and Chemistry , <i>Deep protein representations enable recombinant protein expression prediction.</i> H. Martiny, J. Armenteros, <u>A. Johansen</u> , J. Salomon, H. Nielsen	Journal
2020	Current Research in Biotechnology , <i>Prediction of GPI-Anchored proteins with pointer neural networks.</i> M. Gíslason, H. Nielsen, J. Armenteros, <u>A. Johansen</u>	Journal
2020	IEEE EMBC, Short term blood glucose prediction based on continuous glucose monitoring data. A. Mohebbi, A. Johansen, N. Hansen, P. Christensen, J. Tarp, M. Jensen, H. Bengtsson, M. Mørup	Poster
2020	ICLR, Neural arithmetic units. A. Madsen, <u>A. Johansen</u>	Spotlight
2017	Bioninformatics , <i>An introduction to deep learning on biological sequence data: examples and solutions.</i> V. Jurtz, <u>A. Johansen</u> , M. Nielsen, J. Armenteros, H. Nielsen, C. Sønderby, O. Winther, S. Sønderby	Journal
2017	ACM BCB , Deep recurrent conditional random field for protein secondary structure prediction. <u>A. Johansen</u> , C. Sønderby, S. Sønderby, O. Winther	Oral
2017	IEEE EMBC , <i>A deep learning approach to adherence detection for type 2 diabetics</i> . A. Mohebbi, T. Aradóttir, A. Johansen, H. Bengtsson, M. Fraccaro, M. Mørup	Poster
2016	IEEE ASSP , <i>Epileptiform spike detection via convolutional neural networks</i> . <u>A. Johansen</u> , J. Jin, T. Maszczyk, J. Dauwels, S. Cash, M. Westover	Poster

Patents _____

2017	US Patent App. 15/853,530 , <i>Probability-Based Guider.</i> <u>A. Johansen</u> , B. McCann, J. Bradbury, R. Socher	Pending
2022	US Patent 11250311 , Deep Neural Network-Based Decision Network. A. Johansen, B. McCann, J. Bradbury, R.	Approved
	Socher	Approved